hi welcome back to the meditations for
this middle of the sun alarm rim
retreat and we've reached the fourth
meditation which you will be doing
during the fourth week uh you'll be
doing it during episodes
10 to 12 if i'm correct right
and so you'll be doing it that week that
you're studying episodes 10 to 12.
and we are continuing with the chapter
the 10th chapter from master shantideva
which is called the chapter on
dedication
and uh we are you know
we're in the fourth section of that
meditation now don't forget
what master shantideva is doing
with that section he's dedicating a good
karma what
good karma
i'm finishing the book okay so the 10th
chapter
is the dedication of the writing the
first nine chapters it's kind of cool
so uh he's done this good karma
it's got this big pile of good karma you
know sometimes you get a
unexpected profit from your business you
know
it happens it happens to me from time to
time
and i suddenly i get this big amount of
money
you know and then and then you have to
think of
how you're going to give it away you
know so you can feel that with master
shanti demo
here he's like got this big this big
good karma landed in his hands
of writing the guide to the buddhist
office way of life and now he's going to
have to
he wants to give it away because he
wants to protect it
so he wants to give that good karma to
other people
so we're in the fourth part of that
and you and me uh we're going to try to
emulate shantideva we're going to think
of some
good karma we did and this alarm rim
says
that a small good deed during
a difficult time in the world is a big
good deed
maybe as big as what shantideva did you
see
so normally if there was no virus
being nice to your neighbor wouldn't be
such a big thing but
in the time of the virus to be sweet to
your neighbor to help your neighbor
that becomes a very powerful good karma
it's so powerful
that we can do an act of truth okay
active truth is
we say to ourselves in our meditation
we're gonna say
if it's true that i got to know
the neighbor at the end of my street uh
okay i'll tell you secretly he's uh
he was a marine colonel
and he was a fundamentalist christian
preacher together okay and
and then we never talked to each other
before he's old now
but uh we got to such a sweet
relationship now we worked on it we both
worked on it
uh we didn't start out with a very good
relationship but we worked on it
and the virus helped us so i'm gonna
dedicate this
karma you know that's the good deed i
did
during the virus we became quite close
friends
and i'm very proud of that that's my
llama in practice for
for the last few months uh and i worked
on it and he worked on it i'm sure
so that's the good karma
and then i'm gonna dedicate it i'm gonna
use it for what if it's true
that i became close friends with my
neighbor that we didn't like each other
before the virus
then should the virus itself
be sent to the middle of the sun and
burnt up
for everybody 25 million degrees okay
i'm
by this act of truth which could turn
niagara falls backwards
i i dedicate that act of truth
to shooting the virus into the middle of
the sun for people on this planet okay
so here we go
get ready for your meditation
small smile relaxed forehead
tummy is in virus covid
tummy is pulled in a little bit
hands are comfortable chin mudra if you
like
back is straight shoulders are back
and let's prepare by taking 10 breaths
long exhales that's all
very slow very long
so for this meditation we're going to do
an act of truth
for an act of truth you need some
ammunition you need
a good deed that you have done
particularly in the last few months
during this world crisis
world problem and so
let's each one of us think about
something special thing that we did
that was kind or nice to someone else
during the virus
we all did something that's going to be
our
ammunition
let's think about that
something nice you did during the virus
times just one is enough
make it clear
now let's dedicate that let's do an act
of truth
if it's true then i did this kindness
during the virus then
and here's a list from shantiduma
then may there be beautiful
gardens lovely
gardens appear in this world
and people sitting in those gardens and
enjoying learning goodness
dharma learning learning the dharma it
doesn't have to be buddhist
dharma but may there come to be
beautiful places
maybe this is where we'll have to go
back to teaching dharma in
in large gardens as the in the buddha's
time
with social distancing in the garden and
may there appear gardens in this world
and people relaxing on the grass or on a
bench
speaking about lamrim
if it's true that i was good during the
virus
may there be teachings for everyone may
everyone meet
the teacher who fits them
through my good deed may everyone meet
now shanti deva makes a very interesting
prayer
may the economy of the world
be healthy may the governments be
well managed governments that serve
their peoples
well and of course may the weather be
good
and may the crops be successful and
plentiful
may we have good governance around the
world
may we have good economy world economy
if i was nice during the virus
shanti davis next prayer is very
interesting
it's true that i was good during the
virus to someone
then may medicines in this world be
effective
may medicines work for people
made the vaccine against this virus
be found quickly
and may it work for everybody very
interesting prayer
that shanti deva made over a thousand
years ago
for us
may no one feel pain or fear
may no one be unhappy may no one be hurt
by another person
where people are studying spiritual
practice
whatever religion it may be
may they be successful and may there be
harmony
in that group and may they do good
practice together
may all churches mosques temples
or even people who have no religion may
they live in harmony
may their wisdom increase by my act of
truth
may people believe in higher things
may they learn to make offerings to
higher beings
that they cannot see
may they always be reborn as a human
and may they reach enlightenment
and there are plenty of buddhas in the
universe there are
countless bodhisattvas in the universe
and uh makes an interesting prayer
act of truth
those buddhists and body staffers they
have plans for us
for you for me for our family for our
friends for our country
they have plans for us they are they
have
plans in mind for us
and they may even involve going on a
lower path for a while
but i dedicate the good karma
of the service i gave to others during
the virus
that those plans should come true they
should succeed
in the plans they have for me and for
you those plans should succeed
may all beings see emptiness in this
universe
may all beings practice
loving each other meaning
may they learn to do deep retreat
may places like diamond mountain
grow in many parts of this world where
people can go
and do deep retreat we're doing
sort of a retreat during the virus but
it's good to get out of your own home
and go to a special place where people
just do retreat
and the buildings are built from retreat
made those retreat centers thrive
and be healthy and serve many people
if i have been nice to someone during
the virus try to remember the good thing
you did
send strong prayers to spiritual
communities
of all religions
pray for their success
please come back to your breath three
long exhales
and then slowly open your eyes take a
stretch
nice jump see you in the next meditation